ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.), Carroll, Gene, Files /4354/006
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.), Gene Carroll Files
1986-2013
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Carroll, Gene
New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations (NYSSILR)
New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Metropolitan District Office
/4354/006
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents), photographs.
This collection consists of the files of Gene Carroll, a Cornell University faculty member and co-director of the New York State AFL-CIO/Cornell Union Leadership Institute (ULI).
10632135
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
E. Parker, February 08, 2019
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Gene Carroll is the co-director of the New York State AFL-CIO/Cornell Union Leadership Institute program, which began in 2001 and has more than 450 alumni, most of them based in the metropolitan New York area. The New York State AFL-CIO/Cornell Union Leadership Institute prepares New York's union leaders to more effectively and strategically tackle the tough challenges now facing the labor movement. The Institute is an intensive, one-year executive-level training program for current union leaders and top staff.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4352: Lois Gray Collection of Training Materials /4068: ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office, Anne Nelson Papers /4026: ILR School Metropolitan Office Extension Division Completed Questionnaires on Union Activity /4296: ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.) Training Manuals /4296 AV: ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.) Training Audio-Visual Materials /4321 AV: ILR School Smithers Institute Audio-Visual Materials /4354/006 AV: ILR School Extension Division Metropolitan District Office (New York, N.Y.), Gene Carroll Audio-Visual Materials
Industrial relations -- Study and teaching -- United States; Pittston Coal Group Strike, 1989-1990; Carroll, Gene; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. Metropolitan District Office
10632135
- Cornell University's Labor Breakfast Forums, 1995-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Invitations, speech notes, sign-in sheets, newspaper articles, and correspondence
- Cornell - ILR School History (folder 1 of 2), 1996-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Newspaper clippings on Cornell's finances, unionization efforts by adjuncts and graduate students, Cornell's various campuses, and correspondence re the clippings.
- Cornell - ILR School History (folder 2 of 2), 1986-2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Information on ILR Deans, land grant panel reports, interviews with Lois Gray, materials from the 50th and 60th Anniversaries of the founding of ILR, ULI pamphlets, information on the Buffalo extension offices, and an AdJournal honoring Lois Gray.
- ILR School - 60th Anniversary, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Jobs with Justice - annotated list of members, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Pittston Strike Article (NY Times), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Handwritten rough draft and notes
- Pittston Strike (folder 1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Annotated articles used for research for Pittston article
- Pittston Strike (folder 2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Pittston Strike (folder 3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Photographs (Box 2, Folder 4)
  four color pictures